Guide to the Felix Adler Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Classified Papers
  - Subseries II.2. General Classification (200)
    - 221 Sociology and Economics
      - Property
        - Organization in Business (Box 51, Folder 2b)
        - Jevons’ Theory (Box 51, Folder 2b)
        - The ethics of trade (Box 51, Folder 2b)
        - A. Smith’s. Theory of the moral sentiments (Box 51, Folder 2b)
      - Stammler’s “Wirtschaft & Recht” (Box 51, Folder 3-3a)
      - Labor and Social Problems
        - Visit to Lake Placid (Box 51, Folder 4)
        - Ethics of the Boycott (Box 51, Folder 4)
        - Old Age Insurance – note (Box 51, Folder 4)
        - Crompton's Arbitration (Box 51, Folder 4)
        - Trade Unionism (Box 51, Folder 4)
        - Notes on Labor· (Box 51, Folder 4)
        - Dwellings of the people – Worthington (Box 51, Folder 4)
        - Freedom and Prohibition (Box 51, Folder 4)
        - Problem of the Ethically Minded Wage Earner (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Labor
        - "ProAdams lecture" [series, 5 lectures] (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - Ethics of the boycott (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - Difficulties re: trade unions (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - Injunction and organized labor (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - On boycotts and strikes (Stimson) (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - Labor conference, July 13 (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - Reflections on the labor movement (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - Arbeiter Verhaeltnisse (Brentano-Minghetti) (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - Effect of machinery on wages (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - Progress of the Working Classes (Giffen) (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - Attitude of E.S. to the Labor Movement (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - Strikes (Report of the Royal Commission) (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - Notes (Webb) (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - Chicago Strike Report (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - Improving Labor conditions (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - Notes for an article (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - The Sweating System (Booth) (Box 51, Folder 4a)
        - Freedom and Prohibition (Box 51, Folder 4b)
        - In Reply to Gomper's Invitation (Box 51, Folder 4b)
        - Ethical principle in industrial relations (Box 51, Folder 4b)
        - Shall teachers affiliate with labor unions? (Box 51, Folder 4b)
        - Prospective changes in U.S. government (Box 51, Folder 4b)
        - The Labor Movement in NY (Box 51, Folder 4b)
        - E.M. and the Labor Question (Box 51, Folder 4b)
        - The Stranglehold of the machine (Box 51, Folder 4b)
        - An Ethical Program for the Labor Movement (Box 51, Folder 4b)
        - The Dignity of Labor (Box 51, Folder 4b)
        - 1st session-Arbitration committee (Weber Co.) (Box 51, Folder 4b)
        - Control of Immigration (Box 51, Folder 4b)
        - Improvement of' conditions in Tailoring trade (Box 51, Folder 4b)
        - The saloons (Box 51, Folder 4b)
      - Social Science, Social Law
        - Barth’s Sociology (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - Sociology
        - Baldwin's Mental Development (Box 51, Folder 6)
        - Criticism of Giddings (Box 51, Folder 6)
        - Small's Sociology and Ethics (Box 51, Folder 6)
        - Giddings – Principles of Sociology (Box 51, Folder 6)
        - Baldwin’s “Social and Ethical Interpretations” (Box 51, Folder 6)
        - Relation of Ethics to Social Science (& Notes) (Box 51, Folder 6)
        - Sources of Social Enthusiasm (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Socialism, Property, Social Reform
        - If revolutionary socialism should lead to civil war… (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Capitalism, socialism, opportunism (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Cooperation applied to household life (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Norman Thomas "As I see it" (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Relation of religions to social organization (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - A propos of socialism (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Socialism (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Topics of Social Interest (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - The Social Sense (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Social Philosophy (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Social Reform (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Social Good and Ethical Ideal (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - The Unemployed (Drage) (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Property (Rashdall) (2) (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Outward Conditions and Race Character (Seligman) (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Wounded self-consciousness of the Wealthy (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Economic Justice (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Paradoxes in Human Existence (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Does this world owe you a living (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Ripley on Trusts (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Theory of the Leisure Class (Veblen) (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - Social Topics
        - Society as an organism (Mackenzie) (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Ethical theory of society (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Salient characteristics of modern society (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Definition of society (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Difference between Utopias and parables (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Utopias and visions (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Success in American life (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Altersklassen und Maennerbuende (Schurz) (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Introduction to Social Philosophy (Mackenzie) (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Civilization (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - The Perfect Society (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - American Lawlessness (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - American Idealism (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - American ideals (Roosevelt) (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Relation of immigrant and native population (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Ethics of Social discrimination (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Is Civilization compatible with equality? (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Aims and methods of Social Science (Schaffle) (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Recreation (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Class and Mass (Ghent) (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Notes (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - Settlements
        - The Settlement Idea (Box 51, Folder 9)
        - East Side Enterprise (Box 51, Folder 9)
        - Madison House Celebration (Box 51, Folder 9)
        - 25th Anniversary Settlement Movement (Box 51, Folder 9)
        - 25th Anniversary University Settlement (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - Social Topics
        - The settlement works (Box 51, Folder 9a)
        - Civilization (Box 51, Folder 9a)
        - Social conditions (Bradley) (Box 51, Folder 9a)
        - Distinct Attitude in Social Reform (Box 51, Folder 9a)
        - Shall A Man Live the Life of the Poor Voluntarily? (Box 51, Folder 9a)
        - Social Theory (Seligman) (Box 51, Folder 9a)
        - Genesis of Social conscience (Box 51, Folder 9a)
        - Social Service (Box 51, Folder 9a)
        - Aims of Social Reform (Box 51, Folder 9a)
        - Truthfulness in Social Intercourse (Box 51, Folder 9a)
        - State Socialism (Box 51, Folder 9a)
        - Social Guilt (Box 51, Folder 9a)
        - Real Need of Our Age (Box 51, Folder 9a)
      - The Negro Problem
        - The Negro Problem (Box 51, Folder 10)
        - Dubois- The Negro Problem (Box 51, Folder 10)
        - Points in connection with the Negro problem (Box 51, Folder 10)
      - Social Institutions
        - Institution for Mentally Backward (Box 52, Folder 11)
        - Report of Perkins Institution for the Blind (Box 52, Folder 11)
        - Formation and decay of Voluntary Associations (Box 52, Folder 11)
        - Institution for Advancement of Ethical Standards (Box 52, Folder 11)
        - People’s Inst. And People’s Club (Box 52, Folder 11)
        - Address before Organized Charity Association of Jersey City (Box 52, Folder 11)
        - Notes on Adler's lecture (Social institutions) (Box 52, Folder 11)
      - Child Labor
        - Notes on C.L. (Box 52, Folder 12)
        - Children on the stage (Box 52, Folder 12)
        - Sociological Fund (Illegitimacy) (Box 52, Folder 12)
        - Child Labor Address and notes (Box 52, Folder 12)
        - Reorganization of Family (Box 52, Folder 12)
        - Family Relations (Box 52, Folder 12)
        - Medical Ethics (Foeticide) (Box 52, Folder 12)
        - Child labor meeting, Montclair (Box 52, Folder 12)
        - Child Study Association (Box 52, Folder 12)
      - Progress
        - Idea. of Progress (2) (Box 52, Folder 13)
        - Deep Motive of Human Progress (Box 52, Folder 13)
        - Concerning Progress (Box 52, Folder 13)
        - Wealth and Progress (Gunton) (Box 52, Folder 13)
        - Foes of Human Progress (Box 52, Folder 13)
        - Process of Perfection (Box 52, Folder 13)
        - Science of Social Progress (Box 52, Folder 13)
        - Task of Humanity (3) (Box 52, Folder 13)
        - Trend of the Human Mind (Box 52, Folder 13)
        - Civilization (4) (Box 52, Folder 13)
      - Housing in all countries (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - 221a Sociology and Economics--National Types
      - Science or Nations Primer (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Personal Notes (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Characteristic Peculiarities of the German People (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Three types of Americans (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - German & Eng1ish point of view (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Esquisse psychologique (Fouillée) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Die Amerikaner – Münsterberg (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - German and American Types (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Fouillée – on the Germans (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - National Character (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - 221a Sociology and Economics--Ostrogorski (America) (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - 222 History--Miscellaneous Notes on History
      - Massacre of Saint Bartholomew (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Seely's Roman Imperialism (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Rome (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Feudalism (Luchaire) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Aspects of Feudal system (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Hallam, Middle Ages. France (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Renaissance (Batiffol) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - "Feudalism & commerce" (Adams) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Counter-reformation in Italy (Symonds) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Notes, Hitter's German history (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Remarks on English history (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Parallels between Greek and American history (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Philosophy of History (Woodbridge) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - English History – Kigns (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Dr. Muzzey’s History (2) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Green- Town Life in the 15th Century (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - France (Enc.B) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Feudalism (2) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Symonds (Age of Despots) (2) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - History of Greece and Persia (Meyer) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Greek History (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Roman History (2) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Venice (Enc. Brit) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - German History (3) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Freeman’s Sicily (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Notes on Altamira (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Fall of Dutch Republic (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - History of Islam (Mohammed) (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - ProBurgess ' lectures on American ideal (Berlin) (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - American history (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Memorandum on slavery (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Memorandum on reconstruction (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Concerning history (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Outlines of history (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Notes on History (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Industrial History of England (Gibbons) (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Story of Mankind (Van Loon) (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - History of Slavery (Ingram) (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Poland (Enc. Brit) (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Africa in the 19th Century (Sanderson) (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - South Africa in the 19th Century (Bryce) (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - American History (Epoch Series) (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Spanish History (2) (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - The recrudescence of Leprosy (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Burgess on the American Ideal (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Cheyney – Hart and Fiske [American history] (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Note on the Settlement of America (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Independence of Italian Cities (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Italian history (Enc. Brit) (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Imperial Germany (Von Buelow) (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - The Feudal Principle (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Struggle of the Middle Class with the Feudal Mobility (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Greek and Roman Histories (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Burkhardt's Civilization of the Renaissance (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - The French Revolution (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Notes on English History (Greene) (Box 52, Folder 3)
        (50pp.)
      - The Hinsdale History (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Attic History (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Greek history (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - The Panama Scandal (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Roman History (3) (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - History of New Testament Times (Mathews) (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Introduction to the study of history (Langlois and Seignobos) (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Cambridge History: Mongols (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Rise of the Dutch Republic (Motley) (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - History of the World (Davies) (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Dutch in Java (Day) (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - 223 Law--Miscellaneous Notes on Law
      - Spirit of the Common Law (pound) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Ethical Foundations of A Law of Nations (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Preprofessional school of law (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Note re Cardozo's letter (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - International law (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Notes on the death penalty (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Article "Law" in E.R.E. and notes on 1 article (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Sohm's Roman Law (2) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - International Law (Westlake) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - "The Choice Before Us" (Dickinson) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Sanctity of Law (Salter on Burgess) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Jurisprudence in the Enc. Brit. (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Judiciary Process (Cardozo) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Growth of the law (Cardozo) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Elements of the law (Robinson) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - The Legal concept of Personality (Michoud) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Spiritual Side of the Law (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - New Horizons in Criminal Law (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Punishment of Crime (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - American Lawlessness (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Notes on law (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - On penology (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Vattel – International Law (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - International Ethics pnd International (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Tarde- Les Transformations du droit (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Sohm (Roman Law) (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Testing of Statutes (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Criminal Law (2) (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Freund-Legal nature of Corporations (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - 224 Science--Notes relating to Science
      - Scientific and ethical methods (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Science and religion (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Ends of science and spiritual life (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Pearson's Grammar of science (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - The German history of biology (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Problem of space (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - The Idealization of the Scientific man (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Arrhenius – Das Werden der Welten (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - The Widening Gulf between Science and the unscientific (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - The Unfettered mind (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Science and ethics (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Growth in connection with the warfare of science and religion (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Science and Christian Tradition (Huxley) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Anthropology (Waitz) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Story of the Plants (Grant Allen) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - History of Medicine (Enc. Brit) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Science-notes (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - The Scientific &.rind and the Religious Mind (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Outlines of Science (Thomson) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Some Chemical Problems (Duncan) (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Religion and science (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Remarks on Huxley's Essay (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - 225 Art and Aesthetics
      - General
        - The Mental Concept and Artistic Appreciation (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Tolstoi- What is Art? (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Aristotle- Theory of Art (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - The Classical Ideal (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Symbolism (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Objective Task of the Artist (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Exhibit- Art High School (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Impressionism (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Art Life in the E.S. (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Sepulchral Sculpture (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Point of View of Pictorial Art (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - The Actor’s Art (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Function of Art (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - The classical ideal in Greece (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Notes on actors and acting (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Relation of art to labor (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - The Venetian School (Reinach) (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Eloquence and Art (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Principles of Aesthetics - Parker (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Problem of Evil in Aesthetics (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Address – Robertson Banquet (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Seriousness in Art (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Angel’s Wings (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Muensterberg – Chinese Art (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Works of Art tested by their suitableness (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Municipal Art (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Fundamental Principles of Aesthetics (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Seminar - Additional Notes on Art (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Religious mysticism (Wagner) (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Music and Dancing
        - Rhymic Motion (Box 52, Folder 3)
        - Classicism and Romanticism in Music (Box 52, Folder 3)
        - Cultural Idea Developed in a School for Musical Artists (Box 52, Folder 3)
        - Concerning Musical Beauty (Hanslick) (Box 52, Folder 3)
        - Address to Sargent School (Box 52, Folder 3)
        - Notes for Sargent School (Box 52, Folder 3)
        - Notes for the New Haven Visit (Box 52, Folder 3)
        - Ideal of Culture for a Musician (Box 52, Folder 3)
        - Dance (E.B.) (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Subseries II.3 Single Lectures and Addresses by Dr. Adler (500)
    Several of the 500s have a.n.n.s. by George O’Dell, with references to “publishing writings,” as though he published a collection.
    The Classification of the 500s is as follows:
    501 Ethical Society
    502 Ethical Movement
    503 Ethical Work and Duties
    503 Wealth, Poverty and Morality
    503 Sin and Self Control
    503 Duty and Feelings
    503 Youth and Morality
    503 Wealth
    503 Brotherhood
    503 Affliction and Death
    503 Ethics as a Help to Living
    503 Gambling
    504 Marriage and the Family
    505 Religion
    505.01 Religion and Atheism
    505.02 Religious Change
    506 Religious Holidays
    506.01 New Year's
    507 Social Ethics
    508 Politics
    509 Ethics and Morality
    510 Women
    511 God
    512 Education
    513 Judaism
    514 England; Literature
    515 Anniversary Addresses
    515.01 Anniversaries and Dedications
    516 Christianity
    517 The Preacher
    518 Important Figures
    519 The Bible
    520 War and Peace
    521 Easter Addresses
    522 Evolution
    523 Lectures
    - 501 Ethical Society
      - What Members of the Ethical Society Believe, 1897 May 2 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - A new rule of ethical living, 1925 November 22 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - The Work of Our Society, 1879 October 26 (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - Attitude of the Ethical Society Toward Religion, 1895 December 1 (Box 53, Folder 4)
      - How Far Does the Ethical Society Take the Place of the Church?, 1896 November 8 (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - What Do Members of the Ethical Culture Society Believe In?, 1897 May 2 (Box 53, Folder 6)
      - Future Development of the Ethical Culture Society in New York, 1899 March 26 (Box 53, Folder 7)
      - Ethical Work (Box 53, Folder 8)
      - Progress of the Ethical Movement in New York (Box 53, Folder 9)
      - How Far Does the Ethical Society Take the Place of the Church?, 1896 November 8 (Box 53, Folder 10)
      - Essential Difference Between the Ethical Society and the Churches, 1900 March 4 (Box 53, Folder 10a)
      - What We Stand For, 1893 October 22 (Box 53, Folder 11)
      - Future Development of the Ethical Culture Society in New York, 1899 March 26 (Box 53, Folder 12)
      - Answer to Criticisms of the Ethical Culture (Box 53, Folder 13)
      - The Ethical Culture Society as the Meeting Ground of Gentile and Jew (Box 53, Folder 14)
      - The Recent International Congress of Ethical Societies at Zurich, 1896 October 18 (Box 53, Folder 15)
      - Applied Ethics as a Basis of Union for the Ethical Society (Box 53, Folder 16)
      - Ethical Society (First Lecture of 14th Year) (Box 53, Folder 17)
      - Our Purpose and Our Program, 1885 October 25 (Box 53, Folder 18)
      - Our Work and Aims, 1887 October 16 (Box 53, Folder 19)
      - Our Aims, 1878 October 13 (Box 53, Folder 20)
      - Three Peaks of the Ideal, 1886 October 17 (Box 53, Folder 21)
      - The Ethical Society and Liberalism (Box 53, Folder 22)
      - Words Addressed to an Ethical Leader on His Installation (Box 53, Folder 23)
      - The Society, 1912 March 19 (Box 53, Folder 24)
      - The Attitude of a Religious Society toward the Issues of the Day (Box 53, Folder 25)
      - Consecration address (50th Anniversary), 1913 (Box 54, Folder 26)
      - What Shall We Believe?, 1911 October 22 (Box 54, Folder 27)
      - Ideal of an Ethical Society (Chicago), 1924 October 12 (Box 54, Folder 28)
      - The Service of the Ethical Societies to Mankind, 1920 May 19 (Box 54, Folder 29)
      - The Society, the Platform, etc. (Ethical Leader's Conference) (Box 54, Folder 30)
      - Dedication of the New Meeting House of the Society for Ethical Culture, 1910 October 23 (Box 54, Folder 31)
      - Religious Forms and Ceremonies and Their Counterpart in the Ethical Societies, 1902 December 14 (Box 54, Folder 32)
      - The Ethical Society: What It Means, 1915 May 2 (Box 54, Folder 33)
    - 502 Ethical Movement
      - What Should the Ethical Society Mean to Those Who Belong to It and to the Larger Community?, 1922 October 29 (Box 54, Folder 1)
      - Our Leaders, 1878 October 20 (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - Ethical Culture and Religion (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - Ethical Understanding (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - National Aim of the Ethical Movement, circa 1917 (Box 54, Folder 5)
      - The Meaning of the Ethical Movement (Box 54, Folder 6)
      - Ethics and Culture (Harvard Philoso. Club), 1888 January 9 (Box 54, Folder 7)
      - A Confession of Faith (Box 54, Folder 8)
      - The New Ethical Ideal, 1895 July 14 (Box 54, Folder 9)
      - Ethics and Religion, 1877 March 18 (Box 54, Folder 10)
      - Ethical Culture and Religion (Box 54, Folder 11)
      - The Ethical Society (Box 54, Folder 12)
      - Leadership in the Ethical Movement (A New Vocation) (Box 54, Folder 13)
      - Obstacles to the Ethical Movement (Box 54, Folder 14)
      - The Aims of the Ethical Movement, [1887] (Box 54, Folder 15)
      - Address at New Rochelle [Aims of movement], 1925 April (Box 54, Folder 15a)
      - The Difference Between the Ethical Movement and Liberal Christianity, 1925 November 15 (Box 54, Folder 16)
      - Our Ethical Debt to Christianity and Our Point of Departure From It, 1910 November 13 (Box 54, Folder 16a)
      - Characteristics of the Ethical Movement in America, 1925 June 27 (Box 54, Folder 17)
      - The Ethical Movement After 34 Years, 1910 May 8 (Box 54, Folder 18)